to life.
>> [snorts]
>> Welcome, brothers and sisters, to
another Wednesday question and answer
where we open up with the 10
Commandments that God commanded for the
whole world to keep. Brother Tynsdale.
>> And God spake all these words, saying,
"I am the Lord thy God, which have
brought thee out of the land of Egypt,
out of the house of bondage. Thou shalt
have no other gods before me.
Thou shalt not make thee any graven
image, or any likeness of anything that
is in heaven above, or that is in the
earth beneath, or that is in the water
under the earth. Thou shalt not bow down
thyself to them, nor serve them. For I
the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquities of the fathers
upon the children unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me,
and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain, for the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the sabbath day, to
keep it holy. Six days shalt thou labor,
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou, nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy
manservant, nor thy maidservant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates.
For six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in them is,
and rested the seventh day. Wherefore
the Lord blessed the sabbath day, and
hallowed it. Honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill. Thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
covet thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not covet thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manservant, nor his maidservant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors. We read Exodus 20:1-17.
May the Lord have a blessing to the
reading of his words. In Jesus name we
pray. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
So here on question and answer you can
ask us a question and we'll answer it
according to the King James Bible. And
if we cannot find the answer, we will
seek further counsel to bring you an
answer at a later time. The questions we
will not answer are the vague as well as
the long scripture questions and
questions of debate. We are not here to
debate, we're here to spread the true
gospel of Jesus. So please be as direct
as possible with your questions so we
can be as direct as possible with our
answers out of the King James Bible. No
other Bibles or books will be
acknowledged on this program. Also keep
in mind that this is a live stream, so
feel free to send in your questions that
pertain to everlasting life. We just
asking that you please keep them to a
two scripture maximum. But let me
introduce to you the family that's on
the panel this evening. We got brother
Dre.
>> Good evening.
>> Brother Julius.
>> Good evening everybody.
>> Brother Jerome.
>> Grace and peace.
>> Brother Tanzeel.
>> Good evening everyone.
>> Sister Deborah.
>> Good evening.
>> And we have sister Casey with us as well
as a guest calling and I'm brother
Cornell. And sister Deborah, I know we
got some questions but our viewing
audience would like to know how is it
that they are able to go on and join us
and submit a question?
>> Uh yes, the protocol or procedure
to place a question are the following.
Log in to YouTube.
Be a subscriber for 1 month.
Then you can type your question in the
chat box and add a reference scripture.
You also can go to the previous Q&A and
post a comment there.
>> Okay.
All right. So, we hope that all that had
that question that it has now been
answered. Sister Deborah, let us proceed
with our first question of the evening.
>> Yes, first question. There are those
several
held over questions that will be
answered first before getting into
tonight's Q&A. So, uh Mormon Morty
Waters asked, "Is Israel a place?
I reading was God's name for Jacob and a
new name was Israel. So, Israel was
never really a place. And when it says
land of Israel, it's talking about a
small part in Jerusalem."
>> All right. So, um Brother Jerome, we
need some light on this question. Is
Israel an actual literal place?
>> Well,
um
Israel
uh it's it's actually a country
um
that used to be called the land of
Canaan.
And the Lord promised that land to the
children of Jacob
uh whose name he changed to Israel,
which is one of God's names. So, when
they took over
the land,
you know,
then they changed it
to the land of Israel.
Uh and that land spans way beyond
one city, which is Jerusalem. Jerusalem
is just one city
in in Judah,
which is just a small area
uh in regards to the entire country.
And so, me show you how how large a span
the entire country
of Israel is. Let's go to uh Genesis 15
and let's pick it up at 18.
Genesis 15, pick it up at the verse 18.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> And the
the same day the Lord made a covenant
with Abraham,
saying unto thy seed have I given this
land,
from the river of Egypt unto the great
river of the river Euphrates.
>> Yeah, so it actually spans from
the Nile River all the way to Euphrates
River. And Euphrates River is
is the divider line between Eastern and
Western Europe, but it's kind of like in
that Syria area, Syria.
You know, but it it's it's huge. I'm
just trying to establish that it's huge,
okay? And so
uh one more place, let's go to Ezekiel
36.
Ezekiel 36.
And
let's pick it up at verse 21 and read
the verse 24.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> But I had pity for my holy name,
which the house of Israel had profaned
among the heathens, whether they went.
Therefore say unto the house of Israel,
thus saith the Lord God, I do not this
for your sake, oh house of Israel, but
for my holy name's sake, which ye have
profaned among the heathens, whether ye
went.
And I will sanctify my great name,
which was profaned among the heathens,
which ye have profaned in the midst of
them.
And the heathens shall know
that I am the Lord, saith the Lord God,
when I shall be sanctified in you before
their eyes. For I will take you from
among the heathens, and gather you out
of all countries, and will bring you
into your own land.
>> Yeah, so the Lord going to eventually
bring the children of Israel back to
their own land, and that land span from
the Nile River all the way to the
Euphrates River.
That's all I got on that.
>> Yes, sir. That is their inheritance.
>> All right, brother.
Thank you for that. Hope that answered
their question as we move on to our next
one.
>> Next one, Marquetta Gay asked for you to
explain Jeremiah 30 verse 11.
>> So, Jeremiah 30 and verse 11. Brother
Dre, what you say?
>> Let's go [clears throat] to Jeremiah 30,
and we going to pick it up at verse 10
and read down into it.
Jeremiah 30
verse 10. Can you hear me?
>> Yeah, just a little more volume from you
would be better.
>> Is that a little better?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Jeremiah 30 and verse 10. Go ahead,
brother, when you get it.
>> Therefore fear thou not, O my servant
Jacob, saith the Lord, neither be
dismayed, O Israel: for lo, I will save
thee from afar;
and thy seed from the land of their
captivity;
and Jacob shall return, and shall be in
rest, and be quiet, [clears throat]
and none shall make him afraid.
>> Yes, sir. So, the Lord is going to
deliver Israel. And he's going to
deliver them from all the places where
they've been scattered. Go ahead.
>> For I am with thee, saith the Lord, to
save thee: though I make a full end of
all nations whither I have scattered
thee.
But yet will I not make a full end of
But I will correct thee in measure, and
will not leave thee all together. I'm
punished.
>> So,
here the implication is
that the Lord is going to destroy all
other nations.
But he is he is going to set up his
kingdom, and he's going to be the king
of king and lord of lords. But there
will be other nations.
>> Right.
>> And he said, "I'm not going to leave
Israel all together unpunished." So,
skip down to verse 16 and read that,
brother.
>> Therefore, all they that devour thee
shall be devoured.
>> Mhm.
>> And all that adversaries, every one of
them shall go into captivity.
>> Mhm.
>> They that spoil thee shall be a spoil.
And all that prey upon thee will I give
for a prey.
>> So, if they were if they were made a
full end of, how how can they go into
captivity?
How can they be a spoil? They They
can't. Verse 17, go ahead.
>> But I will restore health unto thee.
>> Mhm.
>> thee of thy wounds, saith the Lord.
>> Cuz they called thee an outcast, saying,
"This is Zion,
whom no man seeketh after."
>> See, so that's that's been our plight
because we sinned against our God.
That's why this condition is resting
upon us. But the Lord is going to
restore Israel.
Skip down to verse 23. Read 23 and 24.
Go ahead.
>> Behold, the whirlwind of the Lord goeth
forth with fury,
a continuing whirlwind.
It shall fall with pain upon the head of
the wicked.
>> Mhm.
>> The fierce anger of the Lord shall not
return until he have done it,
and until he have performed the intent
of his heart.
In the latter days, ye shall consider
it.
>> That's right. So, it's going to fall on
the head of the wicked.
And that is not just the other nations,
but on all people that are wicked.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
So,
that's all I got on that.
>> All right. Thank you for that
explanation. I hope that answered their
question as we move on to our next
question.
>> Next one, Stacy Jones asks, "Is it
lawful for us not to wear fringes and
not having a beard on our faces?"
>> All right, Julius. Is it lawful for us
not to wear fringes and not having a
beard on our faces?
>> No, have nothing to do with the law.
Have nothing to do with the law.
Um
people try to make fringes our culture
and it never never have been, never will
be.
And as a matter of fact, you do not need
them anymore.
First of all, uh Kizzel, let's go to 1
John the uh
1 John the 3rd chapter.
Let's find out why the fringes was
added. Let's find out what sin is first.
1 John 3 and just verse 4.
>> Whosoever committeth sin transgresseth
also the law.
For sin is the transgression of the law.
>> So now, sin is the transgression of the
law. So now,
Israel kept sinning and wouldn't obey
God. Let's go to Numbers the 15th
chapter and read something here.
We're not going to start start it in the
usual place. We're going to start it at
verse 30. Numbers Numbers uh
15 And Kizzel, I want you to start
reading at verse 30.
Let's look at what the Lord said.
>> But the soul that doeth all
presumptuously,
>> Uh-huh.
>> whether he be born in the land
or a stranger, that same reproacheth the
Lord, and that soul that be cut off from
among his people.
>> That soul shall be cut off from among If
he said presumptuously, that mean
willfully.
In the previous verse, the Lord tell you
if you sin through ignorance, but now if
you sin presumptuously, now that soul
shall be cut off. Now he's going to give
you an example and something that was
added to remind you to keep the law. Go
ahead and verse 31.
>> Because he hath despised the word of the
Lord,
>> Uh-huh.
>> and hath broken his commandment.
>> And when you break the commandment, the
wages of sin is death. Go ahead.
>> That soul shall utterly be cut off, and
his iniquity shall be upon him.
>> So now let's get us to the example of
what the transgression of the law
uh uh brings forth. Go here.
>> And while the children of Israel were in
the wilderness, they found a man that
gathered sticks upon the Sabbath day.
>> And the commandment is thou shalt not do
any work on the Sabbath day. Go ahead.
>> And they that found him gathered
gathering sticks brought him unto Moses
and Aaron and unto all the congregation.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And they put him in ward because it was
not declared what should be done to him.
>> So they locked him up and then what did
Moses do? He went and inquired of the
Lord. Go here.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, "The man
shall be surely put to death.
>> Uh-huh.
>> All of the congregation shall stone him
with stones without the camp."
>> Go here.
>> And all the congregation brought him
without the camp and stoned him with
stones, and he died as the Lord
commanded Moses.
>> Now now So the Lord won't continue to
kill the whole camp. He's going to give
them something
to remind you to keep the law. Go here.
>> And the Lord spake unto Moses, saying,
Speak unto the children of Israel, and
bid them that they make them fringes in
the borders of their garment throughout
their generations.
>> Uh-huh.
>> That they put upon the fringes of the
borders a ribbon of blue.
>> Now, now
do you you put these fringes on?
Okay?
A ribbon of blue, but you put the
fringes on. It was added. Okay? Go
ahead.
>> And it shall be unto you for a fringe,
that ye may look upon it and remember
all the commandments of the Lord and do
>> read nowhere where it says this is your
culture. It says, you wear the fringes
and remind you that you look upon and
remember all the commandments of the
Lord and what?
>> And do them.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And that ye seek not after your own
heart and your own eyes, after which ye
use them to go a whoring.
>> Your own heart and your own mind is
Well, to me it means No, you just obey
God. Go ahead.
>> And that ye may remember and do all my
commandments and be holy unto your God.
>> So, now the fringe was added to remind
you to keep the law and that you lean
not to your own understanding. That was
added, not to the 10 commandments. That
was added. But then the first thing that
was added in the Garden of Eden is
death.
The wages of sin is death. So, now,
let's move on. Let's go to Matthew
Let's go to Matthew, the third chapter.
Show you that the fringe was temporary
because when Jesus died, the veil was
rent in twain from top to bottom.
>> Right.
>> That terminated
fringes. That terminated animal
sacrifice, which was also added to
remind you to keep the law. So, the Lord
didn't kill you, he killed your animal.
Now, let's look at somebody who should
have been wearing them, a well-known
prophet.
Matthew
Matthew 3, read verse 1.
>> In those days came John the Baptist
preaching in the wilderness of Judea.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And saying, "Repent ye, for the kingdom
of heaven is at hand."
>> Skip down to verse 4. Now, John the
Baptist, the whole world knew about John
the Baptist. Go ahead to verse 4.
>> And the same John had his raiment of
camel's hair, and a leathern girdle
about his loins.
And his meat was locusts and wild honey.
>> So, where was John's fringes at?
You don't need them.
John should have been wearing fringes.
He was a prophet of the Lord.
Didn't need it because it was
terminated.
It was terminated, sisters and brothers.
So, now, you you don't need the fringes.
The Lord told you in Jeremiah
uh the 33rd chapter, he's going to put
it and Hebrews the 10th chapter, he's
going to put his law in your inward
parts. Now, you don't need to look on
those fringes to remind you thou shalt
not steal, don't commit adultery. Now,
it's in your inward parts. It's in your
inward parts. So,
has nothing to do with uh whether it's
lawful or not. It has nothing to do with
what it was why it was given, to remind
you to keep the law. Now, what's the
second part of that question real quick,
Deborah?
>> Um and not having a beard on your face.
>> Has nothing to do with being a servant
of God. Let me show you. Let me show
you. Let's go to Genesis the 41st
chapter.
Genesis the 41st chapter,
and let's look at
another popular patri- patri- patriarch.
Pick it up at verse 14. 14, Genesis 41
verses 14 to 16. This is Joseph,
the
viceroy of Egypt,
who answered Pharaoh's dream, a servant
of God. Go ahead and read.
>> Then Pharaoh sent and called Joseph, and
they brought him hastily out of the
dungeon.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And he shaved himself
>> And he did what?
>> He shaved himself.
>> Because the Egyptians don't like hair.
So and out of So Joseph went and shaved
himself.
And did what?
>> And changed his raiment, and he came in
unto Pharaoh.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And Pharaoh said unto Joseph, "I have
dreamed a dream, and there is none that
can interpret it. And I have heard say
of thee that thou canst understand a
dream to interpret it."
>> Yes.
>> And Joseph answered Pharaoh, saying,
>> What he mean?
Joseph has shaved himself,
but answered Pharaoh's dream.
Joseph worked for God, sisters and
brothers. You hear what I'm saying?
>> It is not in me,
but God shall give Pharaoh an answer of
peace.
>> Give me verse 25, and we're done.
>> And Joseph said unto Pharaoh,
"The dream of Pharaoh is one. God has
showed Pharaoh what he is about to do."
>> And so God used Joseph to interpret his
dream, uh Pharaoh's dream. Has nothing
to do with having a beard, has nothing
to do with being bald-headed. It has
something to do with being a servant of
God.
>> Right.
>> Yeah.
>> So don't get don't let people trap you
into telling you where you ain't got no
beard, you can't be no servant of God,
you ain't got you bald-headed. Uh cuz if
you read on your own in Second Kings,
the second chapter,
read where Elisha,
a prophet of God,
worked for God. So has nothing to do
with uh
having a bald head or lack of a beard It
something to do with
being a servant of God at all times.
That's all I got. I hope that helped.
>> All right. Thank you for that, brother.
And we hope that they answer that
question there with the answer. All
right, sister Deborah, our next one.
>> Next one, Daddy Two Steps asks, "Is it
an abomination to use contraceptives,
whether married or unmarried?"
>> All right, is it an abomination to use
contraceptives, whether married or
unmarried? Let's go and first deal with
the married. Go to Genesis 1.
Genesis 1. Let's see what the Lord
commanded
our mother and father, Adam and Eve, to
do.
Genesis 1.
And let's pick it up, brother, that
verse 27. Go right ahead.
>> So, God created man in his own image. In
the image of God created he him. Male
and female created he them.
And God blessed them. And God said unto
them, "Be fruitful and multiply, and
replenish the earth, and subdue it, and
have dominion over the fish of the sea,
and over the fowls of the air, and over
every living thing that moveth upon the
earth."
>> All right. So,
that's all I can read about that part
where the Lord gave Adam and Eve, told
them to be fruitful and multiply, and
replenish the earth.
>> Right.
>> All right. Now, let's go to that second
part. They asked about married or
unmarried. Let's go to that 1
Corinthians 7. This is dealing with the
unmarried part of it. 1 Corinthians 7.
And when you get there, brother,
1 Corinthians 7, let's pick it up
at that verse two, because there's
something you can do to avoid
fornicating, fornicating, having
relations outside of your husband or
outside of your wife.
1 Corinthians 7, let's pick it up verse
2 and then we go skip. Go ahead,
brother.
>> Nevertheless, to avoid fornication,
let every man have his own wife.
And let every woman have her own
husband.
>> Oh, so if you want to avoid fornication,
then you have to have your own wife and
you have to have your own husband.
Because relations are for those that are
married, like the Lord told Adam and Eve
in Genesis. Skip down and read 8 and 9.
Go ahead.
>> But I say therefore to the unmarried and
widows,
it is good for them if they abide even
as I.
>> Mhm.
>> But if
they cannot contain,
let them marry.
For it is better to marry
than to burn.
>> Yes, cuz Paul decided to give all his
time to the Lord and everybody can't
abide that way. That is your choice if
you decide not to, but if you cannot
contain yourself
to avoid fornication, hey, that's why
the Lord said get your own wife and get
your own husband cuz it is better for
you to go ahead and marry than it is for
you to burn.
So, that's all I got. Anybody like to
add?
All right, we'll go leave it right
there. We hope that answered your
question as we keep it moving, Dapper.
>> Yes, uh Howard Ames wants you to share
some light on your children dating
living in while living in your house. Uh
he states
his child is 22 years old and in
college.
>> All right, 22 22 years old in college
and then he needs some light on your
children dating while they live inside
your house. Guest caller.
>> Well, as long they're not committing
fornication, there ain't no problem.
>> Mhm.
>> But if they come bringing somebody to
your house and committing fornication
with them, then they shouldn't do be
there.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right, we're going to leave it right
there and move on to that next question.
>> Next one, Valencia says in John 4:36,
where it speaks of wages, does this mean
eternal life for us? And can you explain
verse 38?
>> All right, so we're talking about in
that John 4:36,
is it speaking of wages? Brother Julius.
>> Let's go to that John 4.
Let's go to that John 4.
And
I want to start this at verse 34. Then
we'll skip down to verse 36. Go ahead,
T.
>> And Jesus said unto them, "My meat is to
do the will of him that sent me
and to finish his work."
>> And that is to be And so that was Jesus
meaning that was Jesus
the will of the Father, send the son,
be a sacrifice, kick-start your priest,
kick-start your priest,
and to bring this man back to him, bring
this man back to the Father. Skip down
to verse 36 and go ahead.
>> And he said, "That reapers receive
wages."
>> Start that over.
>> And he that reapeth receiveth wages.
>> Yes.
>> And gathereth fruit unto life eternal.
>> That both he that soweth
and he that reapeth may rejoice
together.
>> Go ahead.
>> And herein is that saying true. One
soweth and another reapeth.
>> Yes.
>> I sent you to reap that whereon ye
bestowed no labor. Other men labored,
and ye are entered into their labors.
>> So now, what this is talking about is
that because the prophets went before
us, Jesus Christ came before us, all the
servants of God came before us. This is
what Jesus explained to the Samaritan
woman and to the Samaritans.
So now,
they did the labor. We are reaping the
benefits of what they did.
They preached the gospel,
and Jesus preached the gospel, all the
prophets preached the gospel, and all
the servants of God preached the gospel.
Now we're preaching the gospel, and so
we all have a chance at eternal life
through the preaching of the gospel. So
we are beneficiaries of those who did
the work before us, laid the foundation
for us. So now, they're going to get
salvation, which is the wages of all of
us, salvation on the right side of the
kingdom, and we would get salvation. So
that's what Jesus is explaining.
So the wages or the payments for you is
the reward of your labor is eternal
life. So everybody laid the groundwork
for us, and we are reaping the benefits.
Now,
just like what we're doing now, other
people can reap the benefits off of our
labors, and it goes so on and so on
until the Lord come back, and at the
end, everybody going to get their
reward, salvation in the kingdom. That's
what that means.
>> Yes, sir. Looking forward to that
salvation. Hope that answered your
question as we continue to move on.
>> Moving on. Linda Stringer says, "Apostle
Paul never met the Lord Jesus before his
death,
but he wrote most of the New Testament
letters. Are Paul's writing personal
letters or divine testimony?"
>> All right. We're talking about Paul
here.
>> Brother Jerome.
No, they not personal
letters. This is is that what he
received from the Lord. That's what he
delivering to the people. Okay? But in
regards to uh Paul seeing the Lord, he
may not have seen him when the Lord came
in the flesh, but
the Lord uh
showed himself unto Paul at at Damascus.
So, let's take a look at that.
Okay? Let's go to Acts the ninth chapter
and read verse 1 through 5, and then
we're going to go to the 26th chapter
after that, Tancel.
>> Okay.
>> Acts the ninth chapter, verse 1 through
5.
>> And Saul,
yet breathing out threatening and
slaughter against the disciples of the
Lord, went into the high priest,
and desired of him letters to Damascus
to the synagogues,
that if he found any of this way,
whether they were men or or women, he
might bring them about to Jerusalem.
And as he journeyed, he came near
Damascus, and suddenly there shined
round about him a light from heaven.
And he fell to the earth,
and heard a voice saying unto him,
"Saul,
Saul,
why persecutest thou me?"
And he said, "Who art thou,
Lord?"
And the Lord said,
"I am Jesus, whom thou persecutest.
It is hard for thee to kick against the
pricks."
>> Yeah. So, um you you also asked
um
are Paul's writings personal letters or
divine
testimony. Let's go to the 26th chapter
of Acts.
Cuz the Lord, after he uh dealt with
Paul in at Damascus, he set him forth on
a mission.
The Lord did, okay? So, it's divine cuz
it's from the Lord. All right? So, uh
uh Acts 26:12-19.
When you get it, go ahead and read.
>> Whereupon as I went to Damascus with
authority and commission from the chief
priest,
at midday, O king, I saw in the way a
light from heaven, above the brightness
of the sun, shining round about me and
them which journeyed with me.
And when we were all fallen to the
earth, I heard a voice speaking unto me
and saying in the Hebrew tongue, "Saul,
Saul, why persecutest thou me? It is
hard for thee to kick against the
pricks."
And I said, "Who art thou, Lord?" And he
said, "I am Jesus whom thou persecutest.
But arise and stand upon thy feet.
For I have appeared unto thee for this
purpose,
to make thee a minister and a witness
both of these things which thou has
seen, and of those things in the which I
will appear unto thee,
delivering thee from the people and from
the Gentiles unto whom now I send thee,
>> Mhm.
>> to open their eyes and to turn them from
darkness to light, and from the power of
Satan unto God, that they may receive
forgiveness of sins
and inheritance among them which are
sanctified by faith that is in me.
>> One more verse.
>> So, whereupon, O king Agrippa, I was not
disobedient unto the heavenly vision.
>> Mhm. Mhm. That's all I got.
>> Mhm.
>> [clears throat]
>> Mhm. All right. Thank you for that,
brother.
Hope they saw the light as we move on to
our next question.
>> Next question. Nate Hudson asks, "Are
women supposed to have their head
covered when listening to gospel church
music?"
>> Are women supposed to have their head
covered when listening to gospel
/ church music? Well, let's open this up
to the panel, but let's kick it off with
that 1 Corinthians 11. Let's go to 1
Corinthians 11.
>> 1 Corinthians 11.
>> And when you get there, brother, read
that 4 and 5.
And this also deals with the woman
having a head covered, and then we'll
open it up to the panel about
gospel and church music. Go ahead,
brother.
>> Every man praying or prophesying having
his head covered dishonoreth his head.
>> Mhm.
>> But every woman that prayeth or
prophesieth with her head uncovered
dishonoreth her head. For that is even
all one as if she were shaven.
>> Yep, so prophesying, spreading the word
of God, women should have their head
covered. Let's open it up to the panel
about what if you're listening to gospel
/ church music?
>> You can't answer that question.
The fifth verse just answered it.
The fifth verse just told you
all you can use. Anything beyond that is
conjecture.
>> All right.
We're going to keep it moving with the
time, chat.
>> Yes, the time is 8:04.
Kylie Parker says in Exodus 12:16,
it says, "No manner of work on this
feast." But my family was wondering,
does this mean we can wash dishes for
non-feast reasons, or the only cleaning
that's to be done is the clean up for
the feast?
>> All right, so
that question started off with Exodus
12:16, Tenzel. Let's go there and read
that, and then the guest caller would
take it there, dealing with um washing
dishes and things of that nature.
>> And in the first day, there shall be a
holy convocation.
And in the seventh day, there shall be a
holy convocation to you. No manner of
work shall be done in them, save that
which every man must eat, that only may
be done of you.
>> Now, it didn't say nothing about every
man must eat. This eating for the feast
is to eat.
So, whatever you use to eat out of, then
you should be able to wash it.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
We'll leave it right there, and we'll go
move on to that next question.
>> Yes, the next one. Philosopher says, "I
have a question regarding Mark 16:9,
which says, 'Now that Jesus was risen
early on the first day of the week.'
With this verse, it says Jesus rose
early on the first day, Sunday.
So, would it be okay for those to
worship his rising on Sunday as long as
they do not partake in Easter pagan
celebrations?"
>> All right, brother Drain. It's Mark
16:9. It's got a little bit in it, but
uh
please share some light, brother.
>> No, you shouldn't
worship on Sunday because he did not
rise on Sunday.
So, let's go to that Mark 16:9.
And and note this also,
that there were no commas and
punctuations
and all of that in the scriptures
when they were originally done.
Man put those things in there. So, when
we read Mark 16,
we going to read it the way that it says
it without the punctuations
and commas.
So, go ahead and read that, brother
Tanza.
>> Now, when Jesus was risen early the
first day of the week, he appeared first
to Mary Magdalene, out of whom he had
cast seven devils.
>> Now, it says, "Now, when Jesus was
risen."
If you pause right there, it says,
"Early the first day of the week,
he appeared to Mary Magdalene, out of
whom he had cast out seven devils."
So, instead of having a pause at week,
the pause should be
"When Now, when Jesus was risen."
Because when they got there, he was
already gone.
>> Right.
>> And it was yet dark still. Now, let's go
over to John the 20th chapter and look
at something there. John 20 and just
read verse 1.
John 20:1.
>> The first day of the week come of Mary
Magdalene early,
when it was yet dark, unto the
sepulchre, and see if the stone taken
away from the sepulchre.
>> Uh-huh. So, when she got there, the
stone was already removed while it was
yet dark.
>> Right.
>> Let's go over to one other place with
this. Let's go to Luke 24.
Luke 24
and pick it up at verse 1.
And read that. So, no, you shouldn't be
celebrating Easter. Easter is pagan.
Don't have nothing to do with Jesus
rising. He had already risen.
>> Right.
>> And they call it Resurrection Sunday
now.
>> Right.
>> But then they have sunrise service.
What are they worshipping?
No, you shouldn't do it. Verse one, go
ahead.
>> Now upon the first day of the week
very early in the morning
they came into the sepulchre bringing
the spices which they had prepared and
certain others with them.
>> Go ahead.
>> And they found the stone rolled away
from the sepulchre.
And they entered in and found not the
body of the Lord Jesus.
>> So, when they entered in the body was
gone. Go ahead.
>> And it came to pass as they were much
perplexed thereabout behold two men
stood by them in shining garments.
>> Mhm.
>> And as they were afraid
and bowed down their faces to the earth,
they said unto them
why seek ye the living among the dead?
>> So, the question was asked, why are you
seeking
the living, the one that's alive among
the dead which are at the cemetery?
>> Right.
>> Jesus, why you seeking the living among
the dead? What does verse six say?
>> He is not here
but is risen.
Remember how he spake unto you when he
was yet in Galilee?
>> That's good. Look, he had already risen.
>> Mhm.
>> He wasn't rising. He did not rise on
Easter Sunday.
>> Right.
>> So, the answer is no.
All right, that's all I got.
>> I'd like I'd like to say something.
>> Yes, sir.
>> You like I said, it's all about
punctuation.
And later on that day
if you go back, let's go back to 20
chapter of uh of uh uh
>> Yeah.
>> John
>> John. And
>> and start reading. We're going to read a
little bit more.
Start at verse one.
>> The first day of the week comeeth Mary
Magdalene early, when it was yet dark,
unto the sepulchre, and seeth the stone
taken away from the sepulchre.
>> Uh-huh.
Great.
>> Then she runneth, and cometh to Simon
Peter, and to the other disciples, whom
Jesus loved, and saith unto them, They
have taken away the Lord out of the
sepulchre, and we know not where they
have laid him.
Then Peter
>> That happened all
That took place while it was dark.
So it couldn't be no sunrise service,
but keep reading.
>> Peter therefore went forth, and that
other disciples that came to the
sepulchre.
And so they ran both together, and the
other disciples did outrun Peter, and
came first to the sepulchre.
And he stooping down, and looking in,
saw the linen clothes lying.
And yet went he not in.
Then cometh Simon Peter following him,
and went into the sepulchre, and seeth
the linen clothes lie,
and the napkin, that was about his head,
not lying with the linen clothes, but
wrapped together in a place by itself.
>> It was well established.
It was well established. He was gone.
Now the apostles came, and they see that
he's not there, but keep reading.
There's one something I want to point
out.
>> Then went in also that other disciple,
which came first to the sepulchre, and
he saw, and believed.
For as yet they knew
For as yet they knew not the scripture,
that he must rise again from the dead.
Then the disciples went away again unto
their own homes.
Then they
>> See the
The disciples came, and they didn't see
him, they went away. So in the meantime,
I'm pretty sure, you know, now this was
the first day of the week. Probably it
was yet dark, but all this activity
I'm pretty sure that
that the sun had to stop start rising,
but still look at all this activity.
Apostles came.
They didn't see nothing till they said,
"Look,
he's gone."
And keep reading.
>> But Mary stood without at the sepulchre
weeping. And as he wept, she stooped
down and looked into the sepulchre.
And see if two angels in white sitting.
And the one at the head and the other at
the feet where the body of Jesus had
laid.
And they said unto her, "Woman, why
weepest thou?" And she said unto them,
"Because they have taken away my Lord,
and I know not where they have laid
him."
And when she had thus said, she turned
herself back and saw Jesus standing, and
knew not that it was Jesus.
>> Now, this is where the confusion came
in. She saw him standing and she spoke
to him on the first day of the week.
>> Mhm.
>> But he was gone when she got there. He
went got the apostles, they couldn't
find him, they left. So she kept hanging
out in the garden trying to figure out
what happened. And the angels, she
inquired of the angel, and later on that
first day of the week,
he showed up
and dealt and and Jesus showed up and
she talked to him on the first day of
the week. It was the conversation that
took place on the first day of the week.
And later on that same day, the first
day of the week, Jesus walked through a
wall and spoke to his apostles.
So he didn't rise on the first day of
the week. It was dark when he got there,
but she did talk to him on the first day
of the week, but he had already risen.
That is what the original uh uh uh uh
passage was talking about. That's all I
have to say.
>> Yes, caller. Can we read that 19th
verse?
>> Read it.
>> Then the same day at evening, being the
first day of the week, when the doors
were
>> You see there? The same day.
That first day, that evening. Go ahead.
>> Being the first day of the week, when
the doors were shut where the disciples
were assembled for fear of the Jews,
came Jesus and stood in the midst and
said unto them, "Peace be unto you."
>> There you go.
>> That's it.
>> All right. Did that mean he rose that
evening?
No. No.
>> He told you from Matthew don't touch me.
I got to go up and be accepted by my
father. He went up and got accepted by
the father and then he came back down
the same day.
>> That's the whole thing in a nutshell,
cuz he had already risen.
Scripture lets you know he rose Saturday
evening before sundown. That's right.
Why is it you going to call yourself
celebrating a pagan festival?
Like the brother said,
no.
>> Yeah. So, yeah. Got that out.
All right. Sister Deborah, we're going
into new territory now.
>> Uh yes, we are. We are now into
tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, April the
15th, 2026.
Uh Bonnie Henderson says, "I was
wondering in Revelations 12 verse 4,
'And his tail drew the third part of the
stars of heaven.' Are these stars evil
angels? Also, in Revelations 8 verse 6
through 12 is this why a third of must
be burned up? So, the first one is
Revelations 12 verse 4. Are these evil
angels?
>> All right. Um
answer that is
uh let's go and read it. And then we
let's open it up
to the panel.
And the answer to that is yeah, evil
angels. Holy ones didn't get cast out.
Go ahead, brother, when you get there.
Revelation 12, read that verse 4, and
then let's open it up to the panel.
>> And his tail drew the third part of the
stars of heaven. And did cast them to
the earth. And the dragon stood before
the woman which was ready to be
delivered
for to devour her child as soon as it
was born.
>> Get down to verse 9, Tenzel.
Yep.
>> And the great dragon was cast out, that
old serpent called the devil and Satan,
which deceiveth
>> Verse 7.
Verse 7.
>> And there was war in heaven.
Michael and his angels fought against
the dragon. And the dragon fought and
his angels and prevailed not. Neither
was their place found any more in
heaven.
And the great dragon was cast out, that
old serpent called the devil and Satan,
which deceiveth the whole world. He was
cast down to the earth. And his angels
was cast out with him.
>> Okay, so that was the third part.
>> Right. So, those weren't
>> angels, which had followed Satan, which
became evil angels and evil spirits.
They was cast out. Now, what was the
other question?
>> The other question is Revelation 8 verse
6 through 12. Is this why a third of
must be burned up?
>> All right. Let's go to that 10 sale
Revelation 8.
And pick it up at that verse 6.
And go ahead, brother.
>> And the seven angels which had the seven
trumpets prepared themselves to sound.
And the first angel sounded, and there
followed hail and fire mingled with
blood. And they were cast upon the
earth.
And the third part of trees was burnt
up, and all green grass was burnt up.
And the second angel sounded, and as it
were a great mountain burning with fire
was cast into the sea. And the third
part of the sea became blood.
>> And we tell more things taking place on
the earth here. Go ahead, brother.
>> And the third part of the creatures
which were in the sea and had life died.
And the third part of the ships were
destroyed.
And the third angel sounded, and there
fell a great star from heaven.
Burning as it were a lamp. And it fell
upon the third part of the rivers and
upon the fountain of waters.
And the name of the star is called
wormwood.
And the third part of the waters became
wormwood, and many men died of the
waters because they were made bitter.
>> Mhm.
>> And the fourth angel sounded, and the
third part of the sun was smitten.
And the third part of the moon, and the
third part of the stars. So as the third
part of them was darkened, and the day
shown not for the third part of it, and
the night likewise.
>> And now this is talking about uh the
Lord dealing with the uh beast and false
prophet.
Can somebody go read where he said he
pulled uh uh his vial out upon the seat
of the beast.
>> All right. Let me search more for that.
Uh 15 and 7 tells about the
vials of golden vials full of the wrath
of God.
If that's where you want to start.
>> Yeah, that that goes uh
uh
This is so much pouring it out up on the
people that have the mark of the beast.
This ain't got nothing to do with the
third with the third part of the angels.
>> All right.
>> So, this is poured out on the seat of
the beast. And and the and the kings
that's going to fight against Jesus, but
still this is the wrath of God. Got
nothing to do with the angels.
>> Okay.
>> So, I guess you can leave it there.
>> Well, um
Okay. I'm going your ways pouring out
the wrath.
>> All right. Cuz it talks about in that 16
and 1
a great voice out of heaven saying, "Go
your ways and pour out the vials of the
wrath of God upon the earth."
>> Uh-huh.
But that's not the whole
Mhm? Go ahead.
>> Start You want to read verse 16 and 1?
>> Yeah, go ahead.
>> And I heard a great voice out of the
temple saying to the seven angels, "Go
your ways and pour out the vials of the
wrath of God upon the earth."
>> Wait.
>> And And that's what happened. He poured
it out on the
upon earth. But he didn't destroy the
whole earth. It was just that one area
he was dealing with.
>> Mhm.
>> So, that's where that's where he come
and actually that's in the area is
called
where the beast and false prophet going
to be set up at. They're going to be set
up in Jerusalem.
>> Yep. Yeah.
>> And the Lord going to come and deal with
them.
>> Yeah. That's right.
>> Third part of that and the third part of
that that's that's the area that he's
smiting because he dealing with the
beast and the false prophet. But the
whole thing is they have nothing to do
with the third part of the angels or the
which are the third part of the star
being thrown out with
with Satan. That's just talking about
what the Lord going to the area of the
earth that the Lord is going to be
smiting.
That's all I'm saying.
>> Yeah.
Okay.
All right. We hope that answered your
question, sister Deborah. We moving on
to the next.
>> Okay. I'm moving on, but I'm
not
sure of
this question that investment fund is
asking
for Judith Julius to answer because I
don't know when this statement was made
or was it made. But investment fund
says, "Brother Julius says something
about a year only having 360
days instead of 365.
Can he explain this?"
>> Oh, okay. Brother Julius talking about
that the Lord's 30 days per month. Go
ahead, brother.
>> Yeah, I might have mentioned that in one
of my lessons.
Man added days, but
it's normally 360
days in a typical year.
How do you know that? Because the great
tribulation is 3 and 1/2 years.
Time times and then divide your time.
1,260 days all that divided by 12 is 360
days.
So, that's the way you explain that. Man
added the years
and gave you 365.
Just like man changed
the times and made
January the first month of the year.
God new year starting in the spring time
around the end of March, beginning of
April in that area. Man starts a new day
in the in the winter time.
Man says that December is the 12th
month.
But
DEC means
10.
Man says October is the 10th month.
But it starts with OCT which is eight.
So, you have to understand God's
calendar and man's calendar.
I hope that helped.
>> Yep.
All right.
I hope that shed some light for you
there as we continue to keep moving.
>> Yes, moving on. Let just stringer says,
I am reading the four winds of heaven.
In Daniel 2:43,
who is they? And that's in quotation
marks of the clay that intermingled
with the seed of man. So, Daniel 2:43,
who is they?
>> All right, why don't we go to Daniel
2:43 and then we'll ask the
the guest caller to weigh in on that.
So, she's talking about the four winds
of heaven. Daniel 2
brother and pick it up at that verse
43.
42 and 43.
>> And as the toes of the feet were part of
iron
and part of clay, so the kingdom shall
be partly strong and partly broken.
And whereas thou sawest iron mixed with
miry clay, they shall mingle themselves
with the seed of men.
But they shall not cleave one to
another, even as iron is not mixed with
clay.
>> All it's talking about is you're going
to have strong nations and then weak
nations.
In fact, you have
you know, like Germany is a strong
nation. You know, and and and and uh uh
France and and a couple of them are
strong, but then some of them are not so
strong.
You know, and uh and when you say you're
going to mingle themselves
he said the seed seed of men, but still
all of them are men. That means that
they are going to mingle as one nation,
uh but they're not going to give up
their identity. Like France
is one of the common uh European Union
nation. Germany is.
France is. Spain.
Right. And Spain and you can go on. You
got 10 of them there and all of them are
retaining their national name. They'll
mingle, but they're not going to give up
their identity.
Some are strong and some are weak.
But either way it is, they 10 toes.
That's mean the 10 nations that make up
the European Union.
>> Mhm.
>> All All of them are
But they going to retain
their identity. That's all I have to
say.
>> All right, thank you for that. Hopefully
that answer their question as we move on
to the next one.
>> Next one. Kenya Haines asked, "Who is
the restrainer
in 2 Thessalonians 2:6
and 7.
>> 2nd Thessalonians 2:6 and 7. Let's go
there, Tanzael.
And they want to know about the
restrainer.
And uh
when you get there, brother,
read that and then let's um
open it up to the panel.
>> 2nd Thessalonians 2:6 and 7.
>> Yes, sir.
>> And now you know
what withholdeth that he might be
revealed in his time.
For the mystery of iniquity doeth
already work. Only he who now letteth
will let until he be taken out of the
way.
>> All right.
So, we know we know we talking
I'm sorry. Go ahead, guest caller.
>> What what is what where is it that the
word restrainer
was?
>> It's not in there.
>> See, that's the whole thing. You know,
like who is the restrainer? I'll tell
you who he's talking about is the
abomination of desolation, the man of
sin.
>> Mhm.
>> I read 2nd Thessalonians uh
2nd chapter and verse 1.
Now we beseech
Start at verse 1.
>> Yep.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Now we beseech you, brethren, by the
coming of our Lord Jesus Christ and by
our gathering together unto him
that you be not soon shaken in mind or
be troubled neither by spirit nor by
word nor by letters as from us as that
the day of Christ is at hand.
Let no man deceive
>> But he's telling you right now, so don't
let nobody tell you uh uh
that Christ can come any day. Like he
can come any day, he can come tomorrow.
He says there's some some things that
must take place before Christ can come.
Read it. Read it.
>> Right.
Let no man deceive you by any means. For
that day shall not come except there
come a falling away first.
And that man of sin be revealed,
the son of perdition.
>> Uh-huh.
>> Who opposeth and exalteth himself above
all that is called God or that is
worshipped, so that he as God sitteth in
the temple of God,
showing himself that he is God.
>> Now, it's simply saying to you that
don't let nobody tell you that Christ is
coming today. First thing is this this
man of sin, he got to he going to stand
in the temple of God. That mean the
temple has got to be built in Jerusalem.
>> Right.
>> And he going to move into this temple
and he going to show himself to be God.
Keep reading.
>> Remember ye not that when I was yet with
you, I told you these things? And now
you know what withholdeth that he might
be revealed in his time.
For the mystery of iniquity doth already
work.
Only he who now
>> He said, "Look, I'm telling you this so
you got some signs. So when you see
this, then these things happen, he will
be revealed in his time." Now continue
to finish that.
>> For the mystery of iniquity doth already
work.
Only he
Only he who now letteth will let
until he be taken out of the way.
>> So the mystery started in the days of
Paul.
That's when they uh
Roman uh uh
was running things
and uh
and the Roman Catholic religion started
during the time of the when when when
after Jesus and during the time Paul
them start. So, they already seen that
the Romans was intervening is because
you had Herod, the Romans made king over
Judea.
And Herod was converted to Judaism.
And Herod has some people running around
with the Sadducees and the Pharisees.
Because they talk about the Herodians.
So,
he had already started to pervert the
word of God
and work toward the abomination of
desolation,
which is also called the man of sin
standing in the temple of God.
So,
he does going to let it happen is the
Lord.
Until it plays out the way prophecy
called it.
That's all I have to say.
>> Could I Could I
Could I Could I throw something in this
guest caller?
This question This question is coming
out of the New King James Bible version.
And it reads at 2 Thessalonians verses 6
and 7 out of the New King James. It
says, "And now you know what is
restraining that he may be revealed in
his own time. For the mystery of
lawlessness is already at work. Only who
who now restrains will do so until he is
taken out of the way." So, this is the
problem with these other Bibles. They
change words and change definitions and
everything and add their own stuff.
Go and stick with the KJV so you can get
the proper understanding.
>> I have some advice for that person that
made that question.
Find it up real good and throw that book
away as far and fast as you can.
>> Yeah, the the thing is
that's also in the ESV and other
versions as well.
>> Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> That's why we read the KJV.
>> Right.
>> That's right.
Why you going to read a book
that was written out of a book
when you have the book that it was
written out of? That don't make sense.
>> right.
Mhm. That's right. Yeah. And and in all
fairness to us, we say in the beginning
of the show that we deal with the King
James Bible only and no other Bibles or
books on this program. So,
like the advice was given, please. Throw
that away. Throw that book away or start
a bonfire with it, either one.
All right.
>> Just like they did in the days of Paul
them when Paul them got to preaching,
they said they brought out all them
books and burned them, didn't they?
>> Yeah, they did.
>> Sure did.
Yeah.
Yes, they did. So.
Mhm.
So, take heed to our advice, please. As
we keep moving, Sister Deborah, with the
time check.
>> Uh yes, the time is 8:34.
Deborah Wilder says,
"I want to know, is it appropriate for
me to check this brother who is defaming
the pastor and the brotherhood with his
negativity comments using the word of
God in social media platform?"
>> Okay. If he is incorrect in his words,
sure. So, he had to check him. Guess
call her. What does she do about
defaming
um
those that are bringing the truth?
>> Check him.
>> That's right.
>> It's all that simple.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
All right.
>> And then
>> We'll move on.
>> And and then, Brother Cornell, uh you
check these people, but this is exactly
what they're looking for. They're
looking for a platform. They can't do
nothing but
Uh
they can't do nothing else so they got
to They're so busy with defaming IOG
that
they want to develop a platform. They're
taking them and leaving them alone.
>> Yeah. And And the book tell us, Julius,
in the last days there'll be mockers of
the truth, right?
>> Yep.
>> Okay. All right. We're going to move on
to our next question, Sister Deborah.
>> Uh yes. Uh JJ Yolster says, "In Luke
16:27,
the suffering rich man asked for a
chance to warn his brothers.
How could he ask Abraham to warn his
brothers if the story took place in the
future? Wouldn't everyone already have
been judged? So, in Luke 16:27,
>> All right.
>> Listen. So,
>> Yes, caller.
>> That took
That took place after
judgment day.
He should have told him, "If you look
around, you'll probably see your
brother." You understand what I'm
saying?
>> Yep.
>> He told See See cuz you will be able to
see them. You'll be able to communicate
with them. But being
this was at the end, go to the
Revelation 20th chapter
and start reading at verse
4.
>> Revelation 20:4.
And I saw thrones, and they that sat
upon them, and judgment was given unto
them. And I saw the souls of them that
were beheaded for the witness of Jesus,
and for the word of God, and which had
not worshipped the beast, neither his
image, neither had received his mark
upon their forehead or in their hands
and they lived and reigned with Christ a
thousand years.
>> Go ahead.
>> But the rest of the dead lived not again
until the thousand years were finished.
This is the first resurrection.
Blessed and holy is he that have part in
the first resurrection. On such the
second death had no power. But they
should be priests of God and of Christ
and shall reign with him a thousand
years.
>> And so that tell you right they tell you
right there that when Jesus was given
that he was talking
after
the thousand years because if you
because only
the righteous going to be raised in the
first resurrection. So this was after
the thousand years.
>> Right.
>> And then if this guy like I said if this
guy look around and that's after the
white throne judgment.
Because the second death is a lake of
fire.
>> That's right.
>> So
And
go and read judgment starting skip down
and start in the books was open.
>> Um
>> In fact start at
uh uh
>> See first read when after the thousand
years was over.
>> Oh okay that would be at the where Satan
is loosed out of his prison.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh-huh.
>> And when the thousand years are expired
Satan shall be loosed out of his prison.
And shall go out to deceive the nations
which are in the four quarters of the
earth God and Magog gather them together
to battle the number of whom is as the
sand of the sea.
And they went up on the breadth of the
earth and compassed the camp of the
saints about. And the beloved city and
fire came down from God out of heaven
and devoured them.
And the devil that deceived them, was
cast into the lake of fire with
brimstone,
where the beast and the false prophet
are, and shall be tormented day and
night forever and ever.
>> Okay. Now, this is Now, I saw throne I
I'm not throne Then the books was open.
>> Okay. And I saw the dead
Wait a minute.
And I saw the dead, small and great,
stand before God, and the books were
opened. And another book was opened,
which is the book of life.
The dead were judged out of those things
which were written in the books
according to their works.
>> Mhm.
>> And the sea gave up the
>> Read the last verse.
>> And whosoever was not found written in
the book of life
was cast into the lake of fire.
>> Well, that let you know right there
that this rich man
did not come out of the grave until
after the thousand years was over with
and after the white throne judgment.
That's mean if you
wasn't right all he had to do was look
around and he would have saw him.
Okay?
>> Yep.
All right.
All right. I hope that answered your
question as we move on to our next one.
>> Uh next one, uh brother Walker uh says
in uh asks in Revelation 18, "When it
talks about Babylon has fallen,
is this the combination of the EU and
man of prediction?" Then he does a
correction and says, "Sin son of
prediction,
who will set up a set up in Jerusalem
during the great tribulation.
So, in Revelation 18, when it talks
about Babylon has fallen,
uh is this a combination of the EU and
son of prediction who will set up in
Jerusalem during the great tribulation?
And they also want to know will the US
be involved?
>> We don't know about the US.
This is same. Go to Revelation 19 and
19.
>> Revelation 19 and 19.
And I saw the beast and the kings of the
earth and their armies gathered together
to make war against him that sat on the
horse and against his army.
And the beast was taken and with him the
false prophet that wrought miracles
before him.
With which he deceived them that had
received the mark of the beast and them
that worshiped his image. These both
were cast alive into a lake of fire
burning with brimstone.
>> So, the temporal leader of the EU and
the spiritual leader of the EU, which is
the Pope, and the man that's called the
beast,
yeah, they are together, one
organization.
That's why I said a woman was riding the
beast in the 13th and 17th chapter of
Revelation.
But as far as America will be in it,
where he said I saw the beast and the
kings of the earth,
there's most likely that America will be
in on that war, too. That'll be World
War III.
That's all I have to say.
>> All right.
Hope that answered your question. Next
one.
>> Uh next one. Israel God is asked, "How
do you know that God hears your
prayers?"
>> All right. How do you know that God
hears your prayers?
>> God won't set in Chronicles 7 on that.
>> Say you going to give account of every
idle word. What you say, Julius?
>> Um let me see here. I think I think uh
Second Chronicles, I want to say Second
Chronicles 7.
Let's go to Second Chronicles 7.
And when you get it, turn there. Read
verse 14.
>> If my people, which are called by my
name,
shall humble themselves
and pray,
and seek my face, and turn from their
wicked ways, then will I hear from
heaven, and will forgive their sin, and
will heal their land.
>> There's your answer. God hears.
>> That's right.
>> The book said that poor man cried,
and the Lord heard him, and delivered
him from out of all of his
afflictions.
God hears. God sees.
>> God hear it all, whether he acts on it
or not.
That's on him.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yes, that's it. Even Matthew 12:36 say
God shall hear every idle word can man
speak.
>> Can we go to Proverbs 15? Just read
verse 29.
>> Proverbs 15.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, one verse, verse 29.
The Lord is far from the wicked, but he
hears the prayer of the righteous.
>> There you go.
>> Yes, sir.
>> How do you know that God hear you?
Because he said he hear you.
>> That's it.
>> That's sufficient.
>> Yep.
>> All right, Sister Deborah, that's is a
ticking, let's keep rolling.
>> Yeah, Charlotte T. says, "My
understanding was that we're not to come
at our wives on the weekly Sabbath. And
they give Exodus 19:10-15.
He says or she says, "But this seems to
indicate that we cannot come at them
anytime
we come nigh unto God. Example, weekly
Sabbaths, annual Sabbaths, etc.
Your thoughts?"
>> All right. Let's begin in Exodus
19:10-15.
That was the question at hand first.
Exodus 19
and we'll go open up to the panel and
it's about coming at your wives and
let's see
what it say here, brother.
And pick it up at that verse nine and
let's see who's speaking here. Go ahead.
>> And the Lord said unto Moses, "Lo, I
come unto thee in a thick cloud, that
the people may hear when I speak with
thee and believe thee forever."
And Moses told the words of the people
unto the Lord.
And the Lord said unto Moses,
"Go unto the people and sanctify them
today and tomorrow and let them wash
their clothes
and be ready against the third day.
For the third day the Lord will come
down in the sight of all the people upon
Mount Sinai.
And thou shalt set bounds unto the
people round about saying, 'Take heed to
yourselves that ye go not up unto the
mount or touch the borders of it.
Whosoever touches the mount
shall be surely put to death.'"
>> Get down to 15. Let's get to that point,
Tenzel. Go ahead.
>> And he said unto the people, "Be ready
against the third day
and come not at your wives."
>> Now, they was speaking about that
particular time.
>> Right.
>> But as far as they being specific on the
Sabbath day, it is talking about we know
it's the weekly Sabbath day.
Whether it's the annual Sabbath day,
it depends on which way it is. But we
don't know. We can only give the answer
that's written in the book. It's talking
about the weekly Sabbath day and it's
talking about that particular time when
the Lord showed up
on Mount Sinai.
Other than that, we ain't got no book
for nothing else.
>> Mhm.
>> And we tell you something that's not
written, then next week you're going to
say, "Show that to me."
>> [laughter]
>> Right.
Okay.
We're going to uh
leave it right there, Deborah. Move on
to the next one.
>> Next one. Look up asked in Matthew
24:15,
"What is and where is the holy place
where the abomination of desolation will
stand?"
>> All right. Read that Matthew 24
>> at 15.
Yeah. Let's read it, Julius, and then
we'll bring you in. Matthew 24 at 15,
Tenzel.
>> When you therefore shall see the
abomination of desolation spoken of by
Daniel the prophet stand in the holy
place,
whoso readeth, let him understand.
>> Julius.
>> That's talking about that temple,
that third temple that they're going to
build that you hear about in the news
all the time, that they're going to
build in Jerusalem.
The the EU army is to place that pope
over there.
In that temple that's going to be built,
he's going to stop the
uh the daily sacrifices, announce
himself to be God, and that's going to
trigger the great tribulation.
It's a place that's going to be built
over right over there in Jerusalem, and
if you alive, you going to see it.
Yeah.
>> That's right.
>> Daniel quoted that from Daniel 11.
>> Uh-huh.
>> All right.
>> Also says in 2 Thessalonians the 2nd
chapter,
>> Yes, sir.
>> man of
sin in the temple of God, showing
himself to be God. That's the temple
that the going to be going to
build over there.
And the pope going to move in it.
>> Yeah.
And it tell you that 2 Thessalonians 2nd
chapter that you going to see it.
Right.
>> That's right.
In fact, it tell you don't believe that
Jesus going to come until you see this.
So, you got to see this before the Lord
before the Lord come, cuz this got to
take place.
>> Yeah.
All right.
We're going to leave it there and move
on to our next question.
>> Our next one, Farren Brooks says, "My
father has read the Ethiopian Bible and
believes that it is the most pure book
and that the KJV is inaccurate.
What can I use to let him know lost
books aren't needed?"
>> All right. Well,
let's call him.
>> Cuz Ethiopians are Hamites.
They followed and got caught under the
whole thing because they black like us.
Ethiopian tried to exterminate
the the tribe of Dan,
the Philistines.
Ethiopians are children of Ham, which
we've been fighting all the time, which
sold us.
And you going to go and read a book that
these Hamites wrote and say this
comprehensive, give me a break.
>> Predicated
That's pred- and that book is predicated
off the Catholic Bible anyway.
Not only that, not only that, on your
own read 2 Thessalonians the second
the 11th chapter and Paul warned you
about the coming of a the and preaching
of another Jesus, another spirit,
another doctrine.
The Lord ain't never made no covenant
with Ham.
>> Plus they got them lost books in there
anyway.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
So, well, that's another book need to be
added to the bonfire. All right. Sister
Deborah, next one.
>> Next one, Yoself uh says, "I'm looking
for a clear understanding about Isaiah
8:20.
When it speaks about the law and the
testimony,
how did the testimony refer to Christ
back
in Isaiah's time, when he didn't come
until later?"
>> All right, well, here goes some light
for you. Let's go to that Isaiah 8.
We're going to open it up to the panel.
Let's read that.
Read that verse 20, Tanasia. Isaiah 8
and verse 20.
>> To the law
and to the testimony. If they speak not
according to this word, it is because
there is no light in them.
>> All right, open to the panel.
Keep reading.
>> Verse 21?
>> Yep.
>> And they shall pass through it, hardly
bestead and hungry.
And it shall to come to pass that when
they shall be hungry,
they shall fret themselves and curse
their king and their God and look
upward.
And they shall look into the earth and
behold trouble and darkness, dimness of
anguish. They shall be driven to
darkness.
>> That's enough.
The reason we know is because of what
Jesus said.
Let's go I think it's in St. John the
5th chapter when Jesus said search the
scripture
>> and then you think you have eternal
life.
But they that they that testify
verse 39.
>> Yes, sir. I think you Yeah.
>> Uh
Yeah. Yeah. I said Tenzel.
>> Search the scriptures for in them you
think you have eternal life.
And they are they which testify me.
>> I get it. And so they already tell you
that somebody going to come and they
going to testify to what has already
been written.
Now
What is it what Jesus said? I think it
was is it
Matthew
27? Somebody go read what Jesus said,
"My God, my God
>> why has thou forsaken me?"
>> That'd be in
Matthew 27 and let's pick it up
Pick it up verse Read 45 and 46, Tenzel.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Now from the sixth hour there was
darkness over all the land unto the
ninth hour.
And about the ninth hour Jesus cried
with a loud voice saying, "Eli, Eli,
lama sabachthani?" That is to say, "My
God, my God, why has thou forsaken me?"
>> Now I your Psalm 22
starting verse one and see what they
say.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Yep, that's Yep, that's it. Psalm 22
Yep.
>> And verse one, brother.
>> My God, my God, why has thou forsaken
me? Why are thou so far from helping me
and from the words of my roaring?
>> So, now that's Jesus to you. And and and
so, what happened is
the prophet said it
and the prophet they also let you know
that somebody going to come along and
testify of it. That's why I showed it to
the law and the testimony, to the old
and the new book. If you don't speak
according to that, ain't no light in you
because it take both of you both of them
for you to get some understanding.
>> Yep.
>> And anybody that say you don't need the
Old Testament,
they are uninformed and vice versa. You
don't need the New Testament, you are
uninformed. It's all that simple.
>> Yep.
>> The The New Testament tell you we have
Peter told you we have a more sure word
of prophecy.
>> Right.
>> That's what he said.
So, they are the testimony.
Testimony The law has put it there now.
They have come along and testified of
it.
>> And Revelation 19 and 10 tell you that
the testimony of Jesus is the spirit of
prophecy.
>> Prophecy, that's right.
Right.
>> So, that spirit of prophecy mean the
word of prophecy.
>> Mhm.
>> If God said it, it's going to be
confirmed. That means somebody going to
testify of it.
>> Sure.
>> And if it ain't no And if it ain't no
testimony of it, then it is not the word
of God. The people that
don't understand that.
So, that's why
So, the whole like you just read,
testimony of Jesus the spirit of
prophecy.
>> Yes, sir.
>> The word of prophecy.
>> All right.
We hope that that answered your question
and sister Deborah as we are winding
very down.
>> Uh yes.
Um
Lovely Cole says, "How can I help
someone to show them that we're not
going to have it and about the rapture?"
>> All right.
Um
we can go read that no man has ascended.
>> Yep.
Go read that.
>> It's John 3 and 3 and 13 directly.
Let me start at 13.
>> That That get direct.
>> Yep, that's it.
And no man have ascended up to heaven,
but he that came down from heaven, even
the Son of man, which is in heaven.
>> That's no man.
Now,
when is When is the dead going to be
raised?
That's in 1 Corinthians the 15th
chapter, where it says
uh uh
you know, uh about the resurrection of
Jesus, every man in his own order.
>> Christ the first fruits.
Yeah.
>> Go read it.
>> All right. 1 Corinthians
15.
Uh
That was 23 where I think he was he was
quoting.
>> Mhm.
>> Start Start there?
>> Verse 22 and 23.
>> Yep. For as in Adam all die, even so in
Christ shall all be made alive. But
every man in his own order.
Christ the first fruits, afterward they
that are Christ at his coming.
>> Are they there? Is Christ here?
>> Nope.
>> Now on your own, you can go into St.
John with the the sixth chapter where he
said four times, "I'm going to raise him
up at the last day."
>> Yes, sir.
>> That's all I have to say.
>> Yeah,
the Bible is not contradicting either
when you talk about Elijah, he didn't go
to the third heaven. He went to what's
called the second heaven, which is the
firmament. You can read that in
You can read that in Genesis where you
talk about it's referred to as heaven.
And that's right.
Yeah.
>> But there's three heavens.
You got no understanding, you don't know
that.
>> Let's go to Genesis 3 and 19, Tenzel.
Show the people what happened when you
when that breath leave your body.
Where you come from?
Genesis 2 and 7 tell you he got you from
Adam from the first man Adam from the
dust of the ground. And let's look at
when you die, where you go. Genesis 3
and 19.
>> In the sweat of thy face
shall thou eat bread till thou return
unto the ground.
>> Until you do what?
>> Return unto the ground.
>> know how people miss that word return.
Go ahead.
>> For out of it was thou taken, for dust
thou art, and unto dust shall thou
return.
>> And that's why Daniel told you
uh in that 12th chapter, Daniel told you
you go sleep in the dust.
>> Right.
>> And they that sleep in the dust shall
awake, some to everlasting life and some
to everlasting shame and contempt.
>> And just like I said in the
but we read earlier.
The people that's going to come up, he's
saying this is the first resurrection.
If it
is the first resurrection when Jesus
come, then
and if somebody's in heaven, then the
Bible lied.
>> That's right. Yeah.
>> Jesus said the meek shall inherit the
earth. Right. He's saying the Lord's
prayer thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done
in earth.
>> That's right.
>> As it is in heaven.
>> That's right. And great day hey the book
say that David is both dead and buried
yet he going to be on the throne, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> [laughter]
>> So
>> And the father going to bring down new
Jerusalem down out of heaven to this
earth.
>> Yeah, so
Deborah was that both parts of that
question? I know they asked about that
heaven part.
>> Uh going to heaven and about the
rapture.
>> Not even in the book.
>> Yeah, not in the book from Genesis to
Revelation can't find nowhere where it
say rapture.
But
we can go to 1 Thessalonians and read
where you'll meet the Lord in the
clouds.
Because it's What's the time check,
Deborah?
>> Uh the time is 9:01.
>> Let's go to 1 Thessalonians 4 and show
when the Lord start his descent, brother
Tenzel.
That it won't be a rapture to be a
meeting.
Verse 16.
1 Thessalonians 4 and 16, brother.
>> The Lord himself shall descend from
heaven with a shout, with a voice of the
archangel, and with the trump of God.
And the dead in Christ shall rise first.
>> Mhm.
>> Then we which are alive and remain shall
be caught up together with them in the
clouds
to meet the Lord in the air.
And so shall we ever be with the Lord.
>> Yes. Yeah.
>> I got to go to Zechariah 14 and show
where that is.
>> Yeah, where Where do we go from there?
>> Go read it.
>> You said Zechariah
Yeah, Zechariah 14.
>> 2 1 to 5.
>> Yeah, yeah.
Behold, the day of the Lord coming. And
that spoils shall be divided in the
midst of thee.
For I will gather all nations against
Jerusalem to battle. And the city shall
be taken. And the
And the houses raffled. And the women
ravished. And half of the city shall go
forth into captivity. And the residue of
the people shall not be cut off from the
city.
Then shall the Lord go forth and fight
against those nations as when he fought
in the day of battle. And his feet shall
stand in that day upon the Mount of
Olives, which is before Jerusalem on the
east.
And the Mount of Olives shall cleave
>> Go ahead.
>> And the Mount of Olives shall cleave in
the midst thereof toward the east and
toward the west. And there shall be a
very great valley. Half of the mountain
shall remove toward the north and half
of it toward the south.
>> [laughter]
>> And you shall flee to the valley of the
mountains. For the valley of the
mountains shall reach unto Azal. Yeah,
you shall flee like as you fled from
before the earthquake in the days of
Uzziah, king of Judah.
And the Lord, my God, shall come
and all the saints with thee.
>> Where did he get them saints from?
>> He met them in the air.
>> I read verse 9.
>> And the Lord shall be king over all the
earth.
In that day there shall be one Lord and
his name one.
>> That's the end of the story.
>> Mhm. Yeah.
All right.
And uh sister Deborah, it's about 9:04,
correct?
>> Correct.
>> All right. Well, we have ran over our
time. It was our pleasure. We enjoyed
sitting down and answering your
questions and we like to say that if you
submitted a question and we didn't have
a chance to get to it, please don't
resubmit it. Sister Deborah will take
your question, put it in rotation, and
we will deal with that
question at our next session. But until
we all come together again, we ask you
to please be safe out there, be blessed,
stay prayed up, and may the Lord have
mercy on us all as brother Tenzel closes
us out.
>> Our Father, which art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done in earth, as it is in
heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread,
and forgive us of our debts, as we
forgive our debtors.
And lead us not into temptation, but
deliver us from evil. For thine is the
kingdom, and the power, and the glory,
forever.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.